易考范文十二
As is vividly depicted in the picture,
a man is exerting himself to grab money in the air,
a voluminous book in hand.
On the book are several big words—academic fraud.
Obviously the painter intends to condemn the intellectuals
who barter their honesty for fame or money.
Recently, mounting negative reports about some prestigious professors
have aroused public concern over intellectual integrity.
These professors, in spite of their high reputation,
are charged with plagiarizing others' research findings
or inventing scientific data.
A reliable survey of 180 researchers indicates that
approximately 60% of them confessed they paid to have papers
published in academic journals and that 40% of them said
they once copied others' work.
To make matters worse,
scholars lacking in professional integrity exert a bad influence on young students,
who followed the trend instead of pursuing innovation.
There is no doubt that this phenomenon has blocked the country's scientific development.
Therefore it is high time that
administration concerned took measures to curb the misconducts
and encourage creativity in academic field.
Of supreme importance is transparency,
which enables the government to oversee researchers’ work.
The eradication of academic dishonesty, I am convinced,
will clear the obstacles that prevent us from becoming a country of innovation and vitality.